我们有一个地方 一个院落
We have a place, a compound.
我们有一个社区
We have a community.
这里很安全
It's safe here.
你们有多少人？
How many of you are there?
其中有小孩吗？
Are any of them children?
沿着河过来是最快的方式
Because the fastest way to get here is by the river,
恐怕你带着小孩来不了
and I don't think you could make it with kids.
听好了 我只说一遍
Listen to me. I'm only gonna say this once.
我们要起程了 这次旅程会很艰苦
We are going on the trip now. It's going to be rough.
你们会觉得路程很长
It's gonna feel like it's going on for a long time,
所以很难保持警惕
so it's gonna be hard to stay alert.
更难保持安静 但你们必须保持警惕和安静
It's gonna be even harder to be quiet, but you have to do both.
你们必须严格按照我说的去做 不然我们到不了
You have to do every single thing I say or we will not make it.
明白吗？
Understand?
你们在任何情况下都不许摘下眼罩
Under no circumstance are you allowed to take off your blindfold.
如果我发现谁摘下眼罩 我会不客气
If I find that you have, I will hurt you.
明不明白？
Do you understand?
天很冷 我们有毯子
It's cold. We have blankets.
男孩 你有你的狗 女孩 你有你的猫
Boy, you have your dog. Girl, you have your kitty.
这里只不过是一个地方 我们不再需要这儿的其他东西
This is just a place. There's nothing more that we need from it.
你们明白吗？
Do you understand?
在河上不许说话
And no talking on the river.
你们一定要仔细听
You must listen as closely as you can.
如果你们听到树林里有动静 你们要告诉我
If you hear something in the woods, you tell me.
如果你们听到水里有动静 也要告诉我
If you hear something in the water, you tell me.
但你们绝对不允许摘下眼罩
But you never, ever take off your blindfold.
如果你们看了 你们就会死
If you look, you will die.
你们明白吗？
Do you understand?
没事的
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- 猫咪。 - 没事的
- Kitty. - It's okay. It's okay.
我们走
Let's go.
好
Okay. Okay.
一 二 三 四 五 六 七 八
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
啊
Ah.
二十八 二十九 三十 这里 没事的
Twenty-eight, 29, 30. Okay, this way. It's fine.
三十一 三十二 三十三
Thirty-one, 32, 33.
在哪儿呢？
Where is it? Where is it?
∮ Whoa ∮
（五年前）
∮ I take as much ∮
∮ As I can get ∮
∮ I don't take ∮
∮ Any regret ∮
∮ I think I'm com-- ∮
-混蛋 我正在听呢 -整条街的人都能听到
- Uh... asshole, I was listening to that. - Yeah, so were the people down the street.
超市里好多人 这件事好像挺严重的
The store was packed. This thing seems serious.
哇 你一点吃的都没有
Wow, you literally have no food.
-什么事？ -你在开玩笑吧？
- What-- What thing? - Are you serious?
-我说真的 -打开新闻 呆瓜
- I'm serious. - Turn on the news, dumb-dumb.
哼 呆瓜
Dumb-dumb.
-哪个频道？呆瓜 -随便哪一个
- What channel, dumb-dumb? - Any one of them.
机场和火车站关闭了
Airports and train stations have shut down.
街道上挤满了开车或行走出逃的人
Streets are crowded with people escaping cities by car and on foot
有目击者举报大量原因不明的自杀
as witnesses report unexplained mass suicides.
首先发起于罗马尼亚
First recorded in Romania,
正在迅速扩散到欧洲和西伯利亚
there's now an alarming spread of incidents into Europe and Siberia.
死亡人数已有数万
Estimated death toll is in the tens of thousands.
目前不知道是什么导致了欧洲和 俄罗斯的大量自杀
...don't yet know what is causing the mass suicides in Europe and Russia.
据目击者说 这些人有精神错乱表现
The eyewitness reports tell of people exhibiting psychotic behavior.
据我们收到的消息
Our sources are telling us
这看起来不是病理或病毒性的
this does not appear to be pathological or viral.
美国政府建议民众保持冷静
US authorities are advising the public to remain calm.
目前没有正式确认的情报…
There have been no officially confirmed inst--
哦 没事 是在俄罗斯
Well, it's in Russia, so...
这话要和那些抢矿泉水的家庭妇女说
Well, try telling that to the soccer moms fighting over bottled water.
说到家庭妇女 我刚给妈妈打完电话
Speaking of which, I just got off the phone with Mom.
怎么总是要我和她说你的情况？
How come I have to update her about you all the time?
-你们为什么一定要说到我呢？ -我可不想跟她聊我的生活
- Why do you have to talk about me? - I'm not telling her about my life.
我三点要去索萨利托看阿拉伯种马
At three o'clock, I'm gonna go check out an Arabian stud in Sausalito.
这句话可不是每天都能听到
See, now that is a sentence you don't hear every day.
-你想去吗？ -我去不了 我约了产科的拉帕姆医生
- You wanna come? - I can't. I've got my OB with Dr. Lapham.
-拉帕姆 什么时候？ -天呐
- Lapham, when? - Oh, my God.
你激动的时候声音为什么那么高？
Why does your voice get high when it gets excited?
-我送你去吧？ -不用 我没事
- How about I drive you? - No, I'm fine.
我可以进去 我们或许可以看看孩子
I can go in. We can maybe see the baby.
或者我可以取消和医生的约定 我们可以去看马
Or I can cancel the appointment and we can go and see a horse.
不要 让马见鬼去吧
No. Fuck the horse.
哇 这么恶毒
Wow. Such venom.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我看到一群人坐在一起
I think I see a whole bunch of people sitting together,
但他们都感觉很孤独
but they all feel incredibly lonely.
孤单是次要的
The loneliness is just incidental.
这幅画讲的是人们缺乏联系的能力
It's really about people's inability to connect.
缺乏和什么联系的能力？
Inability to connect to what?
-能让一下吗？ -马洛里
- Can you move? - Malorie.
-我需要你让一下 -我们讨论过这个
- I need you to move. - We've been through this.
你不会是那样的
- Mm-hmm. - That's not how it's gonna be for you.
你和孩子的感情不一样 那会是一见钟情
It's different with a baby. It's an immediate love affair.
-在我看来不会是那样的 -会的
- It's not gonna be that way for me. - Yes, it will.
-不会的 -你应该对孤独感到害怕
- No, ma'am. - You should be afraid of being alone,
而不是害怕这个
not of this.
我们该做的是带你到外面的世界
And what we need to do is get you...
去和其他人接触
...out into the real world with other people,
而不是整天待在屋子里
not stuck in this house all day. You never leave.
我为什么要出去？ 我有你帮我买日常用品
Why should I leave? I have you to get me groceries.
-你一定要搬家 -我不搬
- You have to move. - No, not moving.
-一定要 -不搬
- Yes, you do. - Not moving.
-为什么？ -我不搬 我喜欢这房子
- Why? - Not moving. I love my house!
我知道你花了不少时间 才找到你喜欢的工作室
I know it took you a long time to find a studio you loved,
自从瑞安走后 你的工作效率变高了
and ever since Ryan left, you've gotten a lot more work done.
但是 现在好了 不再有室友了
But, so fine, so no more roommates.
瑞恩不是我室友
Ryan was not a roommate.
可结果他是的
Uh, it turns out he kind of was.
反正你不能在这里抚养孩子 你连放她的地方都没有
Anyway, can't raise a kid here. Where would you even put her?
你怎么知道是个女孩？
How do you know it's a she?
我只是但愿
Wishful thinking, I guess.
抱歉 工作上有事 我很快就到
Sorry, it's work. I'll be there in a second.
你好
Hi.
对啊，他们只能把手术延后一个小时了
Yeah, they just had to push the surgery back an hour.
是的
Yes?
对
Yeah.
我马上打给你
I'll call right back.
什么？
What?
你还是不想知道孩子的性别吗？
You still don't wanna know the gender?
不想 那只会坏了惊喜
And ruin the surprise, Dr. Lapham? No.
你最近感觉怎么样？ 有没有睡得好一点呢？
How have you been feeling? Have you been sleeping any better?
不好
Rough.
我在有这个症状之前就睡得不好
I never slept well before I had this condition.
这叫做怀孕 你不用不好意思说出口
It's called pregnancy. It's okay to say it out loud.
医生你不知道吗？ 一件事情只要你不承认
Oh, don't you know, Doctor, if you don't acknowledge a thing,
它便会消失
it simply goes away?
哦 真的吗？我怎么不知道？
Oh, really? All this time, I had no idea.
-当一匹马怀孕的时候… -天呐 又是马
- When a horse gets pregnant... - God, the horse.
你懂马吗？
You know about horses?
当一匹马怀孕的时候 它会马上知道
When a horse gets pregnant, it knows right away.
真的吗？
Does it?
它吃东西的方式和走路的样子会改变
It changes the way it eats. It changes its gait.
其他马靠得太近 它会咬
It bites all the other horses who come too close.
-真可惜我们不是马 -是啊
It's too bad we're not horses.
做马真好 这样我们就会有一个
It is too bad. Great to be a horse. Then we would have, like, a mother
真正抚养我们的母亲
who would have actually raised us
和一个在遥远的马场的父亲
and a father off on some faraway stud farm.
等等 我们的父亲确实是在一个遥远的马场
Hold on. Our father was off on a faraway stud farm.
-没错 -没错
- That is correct. - That is correct.
我们真可怜
Poor us.
我们应该借午餐时间喝瓶葡萄酒聊聊 我们有多可怜
We should go feel sorry for ourselves with lunch and a bottle of wine.
你终于开始说人话了
Oh, finally, now you're making some sense.
-好 -你们非要在我面前说喝酒吗？
- Good. - Really, in front of me?
我们不是那个意思
We didn't mean it...
一小杯红酒伤不了这小豌豆
No, like a tiny glass of rosé is not gonna hurt the little bean.
我刚才听到的是喝一瓶酒
I'm pretty sure I heard the word "bottle."
除了小豌豆以外 你也许还得想个名字
You might want to think of a name besides "little bean"
你的孩子已经有一个小甜瓜那么大了
seeing as your child is now the size of a small melon.
小甜瓜！
Small melon!
我知道你很难爱上一个你没见过的人
I know it's hard to love someone you haven't met yet.
哦 你真会说
Oh, that's beautiful.
你有想过把那句话 缝在一个小背包上吗？
Thought about stitching that on, like, a little lavender sachet?
-放在礼品店里可以卖出去 -没错
- Could sell them in the gift shop. - In the gift shop.
马洛里 你要生孩子了
You're having a baby, Malorie.
不久 你、我还有杰西卡 以及一群强悍的产科护士
Pretty soon you and I, Jessica, and some hard-ass labor and delivery nurse
会在三楼开同样的玩笑
will be on the third floor making the same wise cracks.
只是这一次 你不会是一个人回家了
Only this time, you won't be going home by yourself.
我知道
I know. I know.
但如果这不是你想要的
But if that's not what you want,
有很多夫妻渴望着收养一个孩子
there are plenty of couples who are desperate to adopt a child.
这无关对错 你可以做你想做的决定
There are no judgments here. You can make whatever choice you want.
但你不能无视它 希望它就这样消失
But what you can't do is ignore it and hope it just goes away.
（考虑领养？怀孕让人迷惑）
你在里面没事吧？
You okay in there?
我没事
I'm great.
你吐了吗？
Are you puking?
你先到车里去
Just go to the car.
是大块的吗？
Is it chunky?
不是 就是那种直接喷出来 很干净的
No, it was actually the really smooth kind that just shoots out real clean.
我们车里见 好吗？
I'll meet you at the car, okay?
-在走廊里 -走道让出来
- In the corridor. - Let's get it clear.
嘿！警卫！
Hey! Hey! Hey, security!
小心 快来帮帮忙！
Watch out. Help. I need help!
不 退后！
No, get back!
-冷静一点 请你冷静 -一级灰色预警
- Calm down. Please calm down. - Code gray. Level one.
冷静下来 警卫！
Calm down. Security!
-你感觉好点了吗？ -已经开始了
- You feel better? - It's happening now.
有没溅到身上？
You get any on you?
在俄罗斯让大家发疯的东西 到我们这里了
The thing in Russia that's making everybody crazy, it's here now.
-什么？ -拜托你…
- What? - Can you just, please--
等等！
- Hold on. - Inside the hospital.
-医院里 -天呐 快走！
Go, go, go, go!
走！
Go, go, go, go, go!
我们直接去圣罗莎
We're going straight to Santa Rosa.
在这鬼东西结束之前 你待我家
You can stay at my place until whatever the fuck this is isn't.
-我没有衣服 -你可以穿我的
- I don't have any clothes. - You can wear something of mine.
你的马场服饰不适合我
I'm not much of a chaps-and-boots gal.
你现在还在想穿什么？
You're worried about what to wear right now?
想其它事情会给我安慰感
Well, I find it comforting to focus on the wrong things.
-妈的 -怎么了？
- Shit. - What?
马路中间停了一辆车
There's a car stopped in the middle of the fucking road.
-停 你绕过去
Stop. Just go round.
-让开 让我走
Move. Let me go.
这事要是变得更糟 我们就得离开马路
If this thing gets any worse, you'll wanna be off the roads
只能骑马了 相信我
and on a damn horse, trust me.
-天呐！ -妈的
- Oh, my God! - Shit. Shit, shit, shit!
这些人怎么这么傻
People have to stop being so stupid.
天呐 杰西卡 快走
Oh, my God, Jess. Just go. Go.
我有孕妇坐在我车里 我不闯红灯
I'm not running the light with a pregnant lady in the car.
快开！
Just drive the car!
那你让我开 你吓死我了
You gotta let me just drive. You're freaking me out.
-你知道吗？ -你就让我开
- You know what? - Just let me do it.
-不是我的 -我手机在后座
- This isn't me. - My phone is in the back seat.
-是马场工头在找我 -好 静下来想想
- It's the foreman wondering where I am. - Right, just hold your horses.
你把它放哪了？
- Yeah, ha ha. - What did you do with it?
天呐 那是什么东西？
Oh, my God. What the fuck is that?
什么东西？
What the fuck is what?
你看见了什么东西
What the fuck is what? What are you looking at?
你看到了什么？告诉我
What did you see? Talk to me. What the fuck is what?
你在干什么？天呐 杰西卡 别这样
What are you doing? Oh, my God, Jess. Jess, don't do that.
你到底…你怎么了？停下来！
Just what are you-- What is wrong with you? No. Stop it! Stop it!
不要！
No, no, no!
停下！
Stop it! Stop it!
杰西卡你到底怎么了？停下 求你了
Jess, what the fuck is wrong with you? Jess, please. Stop it, Jess.
天呐！停下！
God damn it! Stop it! Please stop it!
快点！
Come on！
-莉迪亚 你在干什么？ -她怀孕了
- Lydia, what are you doing? - She's pregnant.
莉迪亚 现在不行 我们进去
Lydia, not now. Let's go in.
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
你帮不了她！
You can't help!
快点进来！
Hurry, come inside!
好的
Okay.
快点起来 亲爱的
Sweetheart, get up. Right now.
妈妈？
Mom.
别走
Please don't go.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey. Hey.
别往上看
Keep your eyes down.
把门打开 这个女的怀孕了
Open the door. This woman is pregnant.
-把门打开！ -不
- Open the door! - No.
嘿！我是警察 把门打开
- Hey! Open the door. Police.
别开
- Don't open it.
-我是警察！给我把门打开 -对不起
- Police! Open the fucking door! - I'm sorry.
这是我家
It's my house.
进来 快点！
Get in. Hurry!
来 你没事吧？
Come on. You good?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
她去帮你的
She went to help you.
现在她死了
Now she's gone.
大家显然都有一点吓坏了
Come on. Now everybody's obviously just a little freaked out.
-我很抱歉 -进来 到屋里来
- I'm so sorry.?I'm so sorry. - Come in. Come inside the house.
我很抱歉
- I'm so sorry.
来吧
Come on. Come on.
-大家都没事吧？有人受伤吗？ -有没有人有电话信号？
Is everybody all right? -Is anyone getting service in here?
-你没有无线网吗？ -我没有信号
You don't have any Wi-Fi? -I have not gotten any.
拜托了！
Come on.
-不好用 -我得联系上我的孩子
- It's not working. - I gotta get a hold of my kids.
还是没有
No, nothing.
-亲爱的？ -我没有任何信号
- Honey? - Nothing. I have nothing.
-他们在家吗？ -不好意思
- They're at home? - Excuse me.
妈妈 给我打电话 马上打
Mom? Mom, call me. Call me right now.
有事…喂？
Something... Hello? Hello?
它会搞乱你的神经系统
That thing fucks with your nervous system. I've seen it in my clients for weeks.
我在客户体内看到这东西 已经有好几个星期了
I've seen it in my clients for weeks.
嘿 我有没有说我是警察？
Hey, did I mention I'm a fucking cop?
你上警校 不代表你是警察
You're in the Academy. Doesn't make you a cop.
不管这是什么 很快有人会被派过来
Whatever it is, I'm sure they'll send someone soon.
很快会发生的唯一件事是我们都会死
No, the only thing that will happen soon is we're all gonna die soon.
这具有典型的生物战的特征
This has a classic bio-warfare signature.
一定是朝鲜或伊朗
North Korea or Iran.
道格拉斯 目前还没有人知道是什么
Douglas, that's it. They don't know what it is yet, okay?
我们都要保持冷静
We just all gotta try to stay calm.
-是吗？ -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
拜托了
Please.
我们真他妈完蛋了
We are so fucking fucked.
我好像听见了
I think I heard one.
我们正在街上跑 我敢肯定 我感觉到什么
We were running up the street, and I swear to God, I-- I felt something.
-我听到了什么 -你看到了吗？是什么？
- I heard something. - Did you see it? What was it?
我不知道 但我能感觉到
I-- I don't know. It was just there.
-它的存在？ -对
- The presence? - Yeah.
真他妈完蛋了
So fucking fucked.
一定有录像的 一定已经有人发布视频了
Gotta be an image out there. They must have released some video.
-我什么都没看到 -我的工人看见过
- I haven't seen anything. - My crew saw one.
什么？
- What? - What?
我们正在挖地基
One minute, we were digging a foundation...
然后我的承包商躺到了推土机前面
and then my contractor just lies down in front of the bulldozer.
之后我们的司机把推土机开进沟里 折断了他自己的脖子
And then my operator tips the rig into the ditch and snaps his own neck.
好像如果你看它
- Oh. - It seems like if you look at it,
它会让你发疯或者伤害自己
it makes you crazy or it makes you wanna hurt yourself.
不 它会让你自杀
No, it makes you kill yourself.
然后你…
And you just... you just look at it.
-天呐 -…你就看着它
-就会自杀 -怎么会呢？
- And you commit suicide. - How can that be?
关上窗户！
Close the windows. Get the windows!
关上所有窗户
Close all the windows.
大家关上窗户
Everybody, get the windows.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank you, Jesus.
安迪 百利 听见我说话吗？
Andy, Bailey, can you hear me?
爸爸 外面那是什么东西呀？
Dad? What's that thing outside?
-百利！ -百利
- Bailey! Bailey? - Bailey.
百利！
Bailey! Bailey!
-如果你出去 你会死 -我的孩子在外面
- If you go outside, you'll die. - My children are out there!
-让开！ -你到不了你孩子身边！
- Move! - You won't make it to your children!
又有信号了 开响一点
- It's back on. Turn it up.
美国总统已经宣布进入紧急状态
- The President has declared a state of emergency
并且封闭了所有边境
and has closed all borders.
千万不要出门
Do not, do not go outside.
避免使用社交媒体 使用收音机…
Avoid social media. Use radi--
到底他妈怎么回事？
What? What in the shit is happening?
-世界要毁灭了 -什么？
- It's an end game, man. - I'm sorry, what?
世界毁灭
The end game.
人类被审判 我们被判有罪
Humanity has been judged, and we've been found wanting.
-被判决？被谁判决？ -他们有不同的名字
- Judged? By who? - They go by different names.
世界上那么多宗教和传说里面 都有提到过魔鬼
You got world religion and mythology that's full of mentions of demons
或者灵体
or spirit creatures.
看到过这些灵体的人
People who've seen these creatures
几乎每次会在他们的经历里说
almost always describe their encounter as this...
这些灵体会以你最害怕、最伤心
as with an entity that takes on a form of your worst fears or...
或者最令你痛苦的形式现身
your deepest sadness or your greatest loss.
听起来像胡扯 宗教宣传
Sounds like bullshit to me. Religious talk.
这不是胡扯好不好？我说的是真的 这都是事实
It's not bullshit, okay? It's real talk. It's facts.
它们会以不同的形式前来
They come in all different forms.
有阿卡玛纳 还有古琐罗亚斯德传奇里的众迪瓦
You got the Aka Manah, the Varios Daevas from ancient Zoroastrian legend.
还有古基督教神秘信仰里的沙加特
You've got the Surgat from ancient Christian occult beliefs
它会让孕妇把她们的孩子 当做是别的物种
that made pregnant women encounter their unborn children as other creatures
诸如龙虾或者蜘蛛
such as lobsters or spiders.
中国有狐狸精 凯尔特传说里有普卡
You've got the Huli-jing from China. You've got the Puca from Celtic mythology.
不同名字 但它们是同一种东西
All different names, but the same thing.
什么东西？
And what's that?
我们的克星
The end of us.
查理 这都是你在超市上班学来的吗？
Charlie, did you learn all of that working at the supermarket?
-不 我已经研究了很多年了 -在大学里吗？
- No, I've been studying it for years. - In college?
不是你说的大学
Not college per se, but...
我是在网上学的
I mean the Internet.
现在大家都用它来得到信息
That's where you get all your information from.
-我在写小说 大伙 -天呐
- I'm working on a novel, guys. - Fuck's sake.
除了待在这里等着像他一样疯掉 我们无事可干了？
So we can't do anything but wait here until we go crazy like him?
军队一定会来把这些东西控制住的
The army is bound to get this under control.
我们只需要等待
We just have to wait.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
我们何不坐下来？
Why don't we sit back down?
我没事 我只想打个电话
No, no, no. I'm fine. I'm-- I'm just trying to make a call.
-明白 -我没事
- Understood. - I'm okay.
-明白
Understood. Understood. Um...
-电话现在可能用不了 -没事
- The phones aren't working right now. - Okay. Okay.
听着 你有哪里痛吗？
Listen, are you in any pain?
什么？没有
What? No. No.
-我觉得你可能有点脑震荡 -我没事
- I feel like you may have a concussion. - I am fine. I'm fine.
-好吧 -我没事
- Okay. Okay. - I am fine.
-好吧
Okay.
我们刚才在开车
We were just driving.
然后她看到了什么
And then she saw something.
我没看见是什么 但随后她脸上就有这个表情
I didn't see what it was, but then she got this look on her face.
好像她…
It's like she got--
她忽然好伤心 杰西卡通常不会这样
She got so sad, and Jess does not get sad.
从不
No.
她走出车 跑到了马路中间
She stepped out of the car and ran into the street...
她不是会自杀的那种人
and she's not suicidal.
她绝对不会那么做的
She would never do that.
但…
But it was...
还有那个女的 她看到了我
And then that woman-- that woman, she saw me,
然后开始和她妈妈讲话 我…
and then she started talking to her mom and I...
那个女的是我妻子
That woman was my wife.
-她的名字叫莉迪亚 -嗯
- Her name was Lydia. - Okay.
她没有和她母亲讲话 她母亲十年前就去世了
And she wasn't talking to her mother. Her mother's been dead ten years.
（在河上已六小时）
喂
Hello?
喂 有人听见吗？喂
Hello, can anybody hear me? Hello?
Hello? Can anybody hear me? Hello.
有人在吗？ 我的名字叫马洛里
Is anybody out there? Hello, my name is Malorie.
我在河上 有人吗？
I'm on the river. Is anybody out there?
喂？有人吗？
Hello? Hello? Is anybody out there?
有人听见吗？喂
Can anybody hear me? Hello?
马洛里
Malorie. Malorie.
Malorie.
现在已经是事件发生后的第三天
It's been three days since these, um, events unfolded.
电台的线路中断了
Station's lines are down.
我和谁都联系不上
I can't get in touch with anyone.
我们还没有从政府听到任何消息
We haven't heard anything from any authorities...
但是如果你们在听
but if you are listening,
据我所得到的消息看来 只要你待在室内
from what I can gather, as long as you stay indoors,
只要你不看那些东西 你应该不会有事
as long as you don't look at those things...you should be fine.
不要出门
Do not go outside.
我得到任何新消息后会马上通知你们
The moment I receive any more news, I will be sure to update you.
我丈夫在信托和房地产业 你从事哪方面的法律工作？
My husband works in trusts and estates. What kind of law do you practice?
-破产法 -还有就是告邻居
- Bankruptcy. - When he's not suing his neighbors.
嘿 我们的食物能维持多久？
Hey, how long's our food gonna last?
不久了
Not much longer.
因为某些人不懂定量供应是什么意思
Because some of us don't understand the concept of rationing.
道格拉斯 你说你家就在隔壁
Douglas, your house is behind this one.
我们这里忙完了去拿点吃的
When we finish this, let's go for a food run.
我们不会活着回来的 你不明白的在于…
We'd never make it back. What you don't understand is--
-嘿 汤姆 -不能让任何人进来
- Hey, Tom... - We can't let anyone in.
我知道 冷静一下
Okay, just calm down.
-你好 -嗯 你好
- Hello? - Yes, hello.
-你在犯一个大错 -道格拉斯
- You're making a big mistake. - Douglas.
-嗯 你好 -你好？
- Yes, hello. - Hello?
我叫奥林匹亚 我需要帮助 求你了
My name is Olympia. I need help. Please.
-别开门 -我要开门了
- Don't open the goddamn-- - I'm gonna open the door.
操！
Fuck!
好 等一下
Okay, one second.
嘿！
Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey.
让开
Move.
开吧
Go ahead.
拿条毯子来
Go get a-- Go get a blanket. Go get a blanket.
在门的两侧应该有两盏灯
There should be two lamps on either side of the door.
我会给你条毯子 我要你把它挂在两盏灯上面
I'm gonna hand you a blanket and I want you to drape it across the both of them.
-好 -明白吗？
- Okay. - Okay?
我需要你帮我遮住视线
I need you to block the view for me.
-遮住眼睛 -太傻了
- Cover your eyes. - So stupid.
-马洛里 遮住眼睛
Malorie, cover your eyes.
好了 好了
Here. Here. Okay.
好
Okay.
你拿到了就让我知道
Let me know when you have it.
汤姆 这安全吗？
Tom, is this safe?
-闭嘴 -别吵 拜托！
- Shut up. - Hold on, please!
-好了 遮好了 -好
- Okay, it's all covered. - Okay.
进来吧
I got you. Come on.
等等
Hold on. Hold on.
我们没事了
We're good.
-马洛里 -嗯
- Malorie. - Yeah.
-请你把枪放下 -嗯
- The gun, please. - Yeah.
你都不知道怎么用 小心打死别人
Yeah, before you kill someone with it since you have no idea how it works.
没事了
It's okay.
你们…
How...
怎么有那么多人？
There are so many of you.
你是…
So are you, um...
你怀孕了吗？
Are-- Are you pregnant?
是啊 十月一号生
Yeah. October 1st.
你呢？
What about you?
九月底
Uh, end of, uh, September.
等等 外面还是乱成一片吗？
Wait. Hold on. Is shit still going crazy out there or what?
你是一个人吗？
Are you on your own?
是的
Yeah, I am.
我丈夫是空军部队的 上个月被派遣出去了
My husband was deployed last month 'cause he's in the Air Force.
我试图省着吃
I tried to make stuff last as long as I could, um...
但我太饿了 我怕饿了我的孩子
but I was so hungry and I was afraid I would starve my baby,
我不知道该怎么办
so I didn't know what to do.
-来 喝点水 -谢谢你
- Have some water. - Thank you.
所以你出来敲别人家的门？
So you left and started knocking on random doors?
我家离这里只有一个街区
I only live a block away.
太好了 我们都等着在这妇产病房挨饿吧
Great, now we can all starve here in the maternity ward.
这只意味着我们需要补充食物用品
It just means we need to get more supplies.
当然 可我们看不见就什么也拿不了
Of course, but we can't get anything if we can't see.
哦 我们他妈被困在这里了
Oh, we're so fucking trapped.
或许不是
Maybe not.
也许我们不是什么都看不了
Maybe we can see better than we thought.
你什么意思？
- What do you mean?
过来
- Come here.
房子周围有摄像头传输实时监控
We have cameras around the house transmitting a live feed.
上楼 来吧
Come upstairs. Come on.
这只是数字化信号
It's a digitized signal.
它只会显示物体的色温
It just shows the color temperatures of the objects.
这只是被处理过的信息
It's neutered information.
-只是显示器上的图像 -对 但是图像依然可能有力量
- Colors on a flat screen. - But an image can still have power.
我们不知道这些东西是怎么运作的
We have no idea how these things can operate.
这些图像不是直接的
These images are not direct.
我们不能用肉眼看那些东西
We can't look at whatever it is with the naked eye,
但或许我们可以用数字信号来看
but maybe we can with a translator.
只是像素和热量
Pixels and heat.
也许它根本不会出现
Maybe it won't even show up.
不让一个人试试怎么知道？
Well, we're not gonna find out until one of us takes a look.
我看这是一个天大的错
I think it's a huge mistake.
你当然会 道格拉斯 你觉得所有事都是天大的错误
You would, Douglas. You think everything is a huge mistake.
我们早晚都得做些什么
Sooner or later we're gonna have to do something.
我们不知道电还能维持多久
We don't know how long we're gonna have electricity.
你们要相信我 我觉得这能行
You gotta trust me on this. I really think this is gonna work.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
要是管用的话 我们可以用这种科技去拿食物
Maybe if it does, we could use the technology for supply runs or---
没错
Exactly.
别太紧
Just not too tight.
我希望你知道你自己在干什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
听我说 你和你丈夫都是好人
Listen... you and your husband, you're good people.
不是…
You know, it wasn't... It wasn't that.
不是那个什么
谢谢你 道格拉斯
Thank you, Douglas.
你不是必须这样做
You don't have to do this.
我知道 别担心
I know. Don't worry.
-汤姆 我需要遥控器 -是
- Tom, I need the remote. - Yeah.
在这里呢
There you go, bud.
你为什么要告他？
So why are you suing him?
因为他们想把房子的这一侧拆掉
'Cause they want to tear down this part of their house
搭什么大玻璃屋
and build some glass monstrosity.
他丈夫是个建筑师
His husband's an architect.
这是他的房子 他建什么和你有什么关系？
It's his property. Why do you care what he builds?
因为碍我的眼
Because I have to look at it.
你没机会
Not a chance.
世界要结束了 宝贝 谁都说不好
Well, the world's ending, baby, so you never know.
Hmm.
你在哪儿？混蛋
Where are you, motherfucker?
（产前复合维生素）
加油 格雷戈
Come on, Greg.
集中注意
Focus.
这小说是关于世界末日的
It's, uh... It's about the end of the world.
我写的
My novel.
但不像那种儿童故事 拿着弓箭
But it's not one of those kids' stories where they all got crossbows
为了生存互相追杀 或者在一个大迷宫里跑来跑去
and they're killing each other to survive or running around some giant maze.
这个故事...
- Mm-hmm. - No, this story is, um...
这个故事会是很真实的
This story's gonna be real.
你有想过会是像现在这样吗？
Did you ever think it was gonna be anything like this?
-格雷戈 -我们能进来吗？
Greg! Greg, can we come in?
-发生什么了？ -格雷戈
- What's going on? - Greg!
格雷戈 我们能进来吗？
Greg, can we come in?
别看！
Look away!
遮住眼睛 -快找遥控器
Cover your eyes! Cover your eyes. Find the monitor.
-格雷戈
- Greg. - Greg.
格雷戈
- Come on, Greg.
- Greg?
在我这里
- Shit. - I've got it here.
好！可以睁开眼睛了 可以看了
Okay! Okay! Okay! You can open your eyes. You can see.
我早就告诉过他别这样
I fucking told him that it was a mistake.
来吧
Come on.
我们得走了
We got to move. We got to move.
对不起 我真的对不起 - 我们得走了
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. - Come on. We gotta go.
我们永远出不去了
We're never getting out of here.
没有人会来救我们
No one's coming for us.
No one's coming for--
我们得走了
We need to go.
你好
Hi.
我想或许我们走得近一点会更好
Yeah.I thought it might be good for us to be close considering...
当然
Sure.
这样我们就不会孤单了
You know, this way, we won't be lonely.
我在网上看过的文章里说
I read this blog post once about how pregnant women
孕妇应该每天睡在一个人旁边
should always sleep next to someone
因为当母亲有孤独感的时候 胎儿会感受到
because the baby can sense when the mother is lonely.
太好了
Perfect.
你有想过起什么名字吗？
So, um... have you thought about names yet?
还没有
No, not yet.
你呢？
How about you?
如果是女孩 我们想管她叫爱丽儿或者茉莉
Well, if it's a girl we wanted to name her, like, Ariel or Jasmine.
我很想给她取名叫辛德瑞拉 然后直接叫瑞拉
I mean, I would love to name her Cinderella and just call her Ella.
那你丈夫喜欢什么？
And what did your husband like?
我喜欢的他都喜欢
He loves everything I love.
那你呢？你丈夫有喜欢的吗？
What about you? Does your husband have a favorite?
哦 我是一个人
Oh, it's just me.
-抱歉 -不用 没关系
- Oh, I'm-- I'm sorry. - No, it's fine. It's fine.
那你的家人呢？他们一定很兴奋
Well, what about your family? They must be excited--
不好意思 我得出去一下
Do you know what? Could you just excuse me for one second?
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
对不起
Sorry.
看了一次 你忘不掉了
That's something you can't unsee.
肯定忘不掉
Ah, no. No, you cannot.
是
Yeah.
对不起
Sorry.
嘘
Shh.
- Shh, shh. - Hmm.
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我等早上再洗衣服吧
I'll wait to do my laundry in the morning.
-那样更好 -没错
- That's probably a good idea. - Yeah, I think so.
晚安
Good night.
（在河上已十四小时）
喂！
Hello!
你们需要帮忙吗？
You guys need some help?
-你们可以摘掉你们的眼罩 -千万不要把眼罩摘下！
- It's okay to take your blindfolds off. - Do not take your blindfolds off. Do not!
我这里有吃的 孩子们一定饿了吧
I got some food. Those kids look hungry.
蹲下！快点
Get down! Get down! Get down! Down. Down. Down.
嘿 小朋友们
Hey, little buddies.
你们有没有见过小鹿？
Have you ever seen a baby deer?
我告诉你们一个秘密
I'll tell you a secret.
我在树林里找到了一只
I found one in the woods.
我知道你们很害怕 但没有这个必要
Okay. I know you're scared. Well, listen, there's no need.
我不是来伤害你们的 我可以拉你们上岸
I'm not here to hurt you. I can pull you to shore.
把你的眼罩给我摘下！
Take your goddamn blindfold off!
啊
Ah!
我看到过 我见过真相
I've seen one. I've seen the truth.
把你的眼罩摘下
Take your blindfold off.
它很美丽的 摘下你的眼罩
It's beautiful. It's beautiful. Take your blindfold off.
摘下你的眼罩！
Take your blindfold off!
它将净化这个世界
It shall cleanse the world!
每个人都必须看
Everyone must look.
我有坏消息要宣布
Got some bad news.
我们快没有食物了 没有人会来救我们
All right. We're running out of food and there's no help coming.
我们必须出去
We've got to get outside.
我知道哪里有吃的
Look, I might know where we can get more.
-在哪？查理 -在我工作的超市
- Where, Charlie? - The Fields market.
当事件爆发以后 我把超市锁起来了
I locked the place up when everything started going crazy.
-你怎么到现在才告诉我们 -至少我们现在知道了
- You're just telling us this? - At least we know now.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们需要一队人
Okay, so we'll need a group of us to go.
我们还没到那儿 就肯定死光了
Whoa. We'll be dead before we get there.
-别开玩笑了 -我去
- Are you kidding me? - I'll go.
-他去 我也去 -你怀孕了
- Well, if he's going, I'm going. - You're pregnant!
如果你们都去的话 那我也去
Well, if all you guys are going, then I can come too.
要不这次我去 下次你去
Why don't I go on the first run and then you can go on the second run?
-我也去 -什么？
- I'll come. - What?
-你这是求死 -我有训练过 没事的
- It's a death wish. - I have the training. It'll be fine.
我有不好的感觉 我觉得大家还是都别去
I don't like this. I don't think anyone should go.
-我们有四个人 -五个 查理也去
- There are four of us. - Five. Charlie's going.
查理也去？查理哪儿也不去
Charlie's going? Charlie ain't going nowhere.
-你了解防盗系统 -我绝对不会去的 好吗？
- You know the security system. - No chance I'm going.
我给你们提供了信息
I gave you the information. That's all you needed.
你不需要我给你们指路 那是个超市
You don't need me to tell you where to go. It is a supermarket.
超市有标牌 你们去超市买过东西
They got signs. You've been shopping before.
你想买谷物 牌子上会写着谷物
You wanna get cereal, the sign will say cereals.
如果你们不识字 我能理解 但你们识字
If you can't read, I get it, but you can read.
-你们不需要我和你们一起去 -查理 这可以为你的小说提供素材
- No. You don't need me to go with you-- - Charlie. It'll be research for the book.
怎么样？会很棒的
Okay? Be awesome.
如果我们可以遮住所有车窗
All right, so the idea is if we can black out all the windows,
既有效率又安全
it's efficient and it's safe.
有人在听这话吗？
Is anybody else hearing this?
盲着开车怎么会安全？
How is driving blind safer?
我们不是盲着
We're not.
我们有导航仪
We've got the GPS.
正在计算行程
Calculating route.
继续直行
Continue straight.
在800米后右转进入海岸街
In half a mile, turn right onto Bay Street.
-怎么回事？ -压到路牙子了
- What is that? - It's a curb.
路牙子
It's just a curb.
那是距离感测器
It's a proximity sensor.
只是个路面减速带
Just a speed bump. It's just a speed bump.
右转
Turn right here.
-我们不在马路上了吗？ -没有 有东西
- Are we off the road? - No, there's something.
-我觉得应该是个卡车 -绕过去
- I think it must be just a truck. - Just go around.
-一直绕过它 -嗯
- Keep going around it. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
怎么回事？
What was that?
外面有其他人在开车吗？
Is somebody else driving out there?
-操！去他妈的 -查理 冷静一下
- Charlie, breathe. - Shit! Fuck this shit.
-出去！ -查理！冷静
- Get the fuck out! - Charlie! Calm down.
大伙别碰他了
Guys, stop touching him.
-看着我 你一定要小声点 -让他闭嘴
- Look at me. You have to be quiet. - Shut him up.
啊
Ah. Ah!
操！我们要死了
Fuck! We're not gonna make it.
冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
-天呐！ -大家抓紧了
- Oh, shit! - Everybody, hold on.
抓紧了 我们要走了！
Hold on to something. Gonna move!
啊
Ah!
抓好！
Hold on!
那可不是路面减速带！
That's not a fucking speed bump!
-操 卡住了 -抓紧
- Fuck, it's stuck. - Hold on.
左转
- Turn left here.
慢点！
- Slow down! Slow down!
已到达目的地
You have arrived.
怎么回事？
What the fuck?
经历了刚才的事情后 我们现在要下车吗？
And after all this, we're supposed to get out now?
我们真幸运
Lucky us.
-我数三下 一… -我准备好了
- On three. One... - I'm ready now.
…二 三
...two, three.
那是什么？我撞到了什么？
What was that? What did I just hit?
是一根柱子
That's just a pillar.
好 门在…
Okay. Where's the--
再走几步应该就到门了
The door should be just a couple of paces up, man.
-我找不到 -在你左边
- I'm lost. - Towards your left.
左边
Left. Left.
我找不到
I'm lost.
-大伙跟上 -我找不到
- Come on, you guys. - I'm lost.
-哦 在这里 -好
- Oh, here. Here. - Okay. Okay.
-打开了吗？ -还没
- You're in? - No.
等等 马上就好
Okay. Wait. Almost got it.
好 打开了
Okay, I got it.
进去
Go on.
好 我们进来了
All right. We're in.
有人吗？嘘
- Hello! - Shh! Shh!
我关窗帘
I'll check the windows.
这里
Here we go. Here we go.
我们应该没事了 你们可以摘下眼罩
All right,?I think we're clear. You can take 'em off.
天呐
Oh, my God.
-我们真是来对地方了 -是啊
- Jack-fucking-pot. - Yeah.
-罐头食品在哪？ -第二排
- Where are the canned goods? - Aisle two.
-卫生纸呢？ -第五排
- Toilet paper? - Five.
-谁要卫生纸 酒在哪？ -在第七排
- Fuck that. Where's the booze? - It's in seven.
别忘了我们的空间有限 只拿不易腐烂的和必需品
Let's not forget. We have limited space. Stick to non-perishables, the necessities.
-电器在哪儿？ -在第六排
- Where are the electronics? - Go to six.
第六排 好 谢谢
Six. All right. Cool. Thank you.
我可不收拾这些垃圾
I'm not cleaning this shit up.
太好了
Sweet.
真高兴我跟着一起来
Boy, I'm glad I tagged along.
这真的是这世界上最美好的地方
This is truly the happiest place on Earth.
我知道 你说得没错！
I know. You're not kidding!
这是我给你的迎婴洗礼礼物
It's, uh... my baby shower gift to you.
谢谢你
Why, thank you.
嗯
Yeah.
我姐姐要生第四个孩子了
So, my sister is expecting her fourth, so...
天呐 她真是个圣人
Oh, my God. She's a saint.
她的确是
Yeah, she is.
我经常摸她肚子
And I'm always touching her belly.
很有舒缓作用
It's calming.
是啊 是大自然耍的小花样
Yeah, it's nature's dirty little trick.
你姐姐住在萨克拉门托吗？
Is your sister in Sacramento?
-是的 -是吗？
- Yeah. - Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
那你呢？你在哪儿长大的？
What about you? Where did you-- Where did you grow up?
斯托克顿城外
Oh, just outside of Stockton.
-斯托克顿 -对
- Stockton. - Yeah.
-我们家是养马的 -在真的马场吗？
- We raised horses. - On a real ranch?
-我老爸是个真正的牛仔 -你就是从那里学来的…
- Well, my daddy was a real cowboy. - That's--That's how you learned your...
-什么？ -…散弹枪技术
- What? - ...little shotgun trick.
是 我的童年很有趣
Yeah. I had an interesting childhood.
Hmm.
但托克顿离萨克拉门托不远
Ah, but Stockton wasn't all that far from Sacramento.
不远 顺着99号高速过去
No. Just down 99.
-99号高速 没错 -区别很大 是吗？
- Just down Highway 99. - Worlds apart, right?
我们仍然可能在其他情况下认识
Still we could've met some other way.
当然
Sure.
我也有可能做你的保姆
Could have been your babysitter.
性感的保姆
My hot babysitter.
你这么说只是因为我们都快要死了
You're... You're only saying that 'cause we're all gonna die.
或许吧
Possibly.
你们怎么那么幸运？
How did you guys get so lucky?
哈？
Huh?
嗨
Hi.
你们好
Hi, there.
好困
So sleepy.
所有顾客注意 请到第七排来
Attention, all shoppers, come to aisle seven, please.
我有一件很大的事要宣布
I have a?big, big, big, big, big announcement to make.
-女士们先生们 请… -什么事？道格拉斯
- Ladies and gentlemen, please... - Yes, Douglas.
我想借此机会发表祝酒词 敬我们大家
I would like to take this opportunity to make a toast to all of us...
因为我们一起让世界末日…
because all of us, collectively, are making the end of the world...
再一次美好！
great again! Yeah!
小鸟
Birdies.
你们这帮笨蛋到现在还不明白吗？
I mean, don't you doofuses get it?
我可以待在这里
Uh, we could just stay here.
这里有我们一年的吃喝用品
We have a year's supply of food and drink right here.
我们不用花钱 我们不应该走
We don't ever have to pay and we shouldn't ever leave.
那在格雷戈家里的人怎么办？ 等着饿死吗？
And what are they gonna do at Greg's? Starve?
比我们饿死好
Better them than us.
这里有我们生活需要的一切
We have everything we need to live here. Everything.
我们在统计学、逻辑和法律的角度上 没有任何理由回去
There is no statistical, logical, or legal argument for trying to get back there.
我给你个理由 我们不是混蛋
Here's an argument: we're not assholes.
我们不能待在这里
And we're not staying.
怎么回事？
What is it?
查理 那里面是什么？
- Somebody let me out of here. - Charlie, what's behind there?
是装货码头
It's a loading dock.
你好？
Hello?
让我进来
Please let me in.
大声点 我听不见
Speak up, I can't hear you.
请让我进来
Please let me in.
遮住眼睛
Cover your eyes.
-什么？ -我要开门了
- What? - I'm gonna open the door.
-不行 -外面有个人
- No. - There's a person out there.
我一定要开
I have to open the door.
好
Okay.
Okay. Uh...
好
Okay.
-你好 -你好
- Hello? - Hello.
让我进来 我被困了
Please let me in. I'm trapped.
等等 鱼条 是你吗？
Wait, wait, wait. Is that... Fish Fingers, is that you?
-查理 对 是我 -查理 谁是鱼条？
- Charlie, yeah, it's me. - Who's Fish Fingers, Charlie?
他和我一起在这超市上班 他在海鲜部工作
He works here at the supermarket with me. He works in the seafood department.
他坐过牢 有点疯 但一直对我挺好的
He's been to prison and he's a bit crazy, but he's always nice to me.
-你是怎么进去的？ -我…
- How did you get there, man? - I got... I got...
他们骗了我
They tricked me!
他们是谁？
Who's they?
你在指谁？你是一个人吗？
Who you talking about? Are you there alone?
他们骗了我 他们把我丢在这里等死
They tricked me and they left me to rot here.
谁把你丢在那里等死？你在说什么？
Who left you to rot? What are you talking about?
大伙 有事不对劲
You guys, there's something wrong.
-有事不对劲！ -让我进来 我被困了
There's something wrong!
- Please let me in. I'm trapped.
嘿 嘿 嘿
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
你在干嘛？鱼条 你在干嘛呢？
What are you doin', Fish Fingers? What are you doing, man?
朝它看 它想让你看到它 让我进来！
Look at it! It wants you to see it! Let me in!
他力气太大了 我挡不住他
He's too strong. I can't hold him.
让我进来！
Let me in!
妈的
Shit!
查理！
Charlie! Charlie! Charlie!
操！
Fuck! Ah!
查理 等等！
Charlie, wait!
看 查理 它很美
Look at it, Charlie. It's beautiful.
-查理？ -查理！
- Charlie? - Charlie!
-查理！ -查理！
- Charlie! - Charlie!
-妈的 -见鬼！
- Oh, shit. - Oh, fuck.
天呐！
Fuck!
我们得走了
We gotta go.
我们得走了 快点 我们走
We gotta move. Come on. Let's go.
快点离开这里
Let's get out of here.
让我进来
Please. Please let me in.
那个人怎么还活着？
How is that guy alive in there?
让我进来
Please let me in.
费利克斯！
Hi, Felix!
天呐
Oh, my God.
看有好多东西
Look at all this stuff.
-小鸟？ -对
- Birdies? - Yeah, they, uh...
它们会感觉到灵体靠近
They seem to sense when the creatures are around.
查理呢？
Where's Charlie?
这样我就不用读他的小说了
Another novel I won't have to read.
他救了我们 你这个混蛋
He saved us, you fucking asshole.
我知道你对我是什么看法 也知道大家对我的看法
I know what you think of me, what everybody thinks of me.
在离婚申请书上
You know, in the divorce petition...
我第一个妻子说 管我叫混蛋是对混蛋的侮辱
my first wife said that to call me a creep would be an affront to creeps everywhere.
我第二个妻子说她再也不怕下地狱
My second wife said she no longer feared going to hell,
因为地狱不可能比和我在一起还要差
'cause it couldn't possibly be worse than being married to me.
我想她们很适合做我朋友
Think I would have loved them.
或许吧
Maybe.
后来我娶了莉迪亚
And then Lydia.
第三次婚姻可真是我的福气
Third time really was the charm for me.
她是我见过最善良的人
She was the kindest person I ever met.
可是她走了 而我还在 你知道为什么吗？
But I'm here and she's gone. You know why that is?
因为最终这世上只剩两种人
Because, in the end, there are only two types of people.
一种是混蛋 一种是死人
The assholes and the dead.
天呐 你听上去像我父亲
God, you sound like my father.
像你父亲？为什么？
Like your father? Why?
他是一个教导傻瓜的智者吗？
Was he a towering intellect given to dispensing wisdom to undeserving fools?
没错 也很会说风凉话
Yes, he was fluent in asshole as well.
像你一样 他做的所有事 都会归咎于一些大道理
And just like you, he blamed everything he did on some deeper meaning,
一些错综复杂的阴谋论
convoluted conspiracy theories and...
即使他明显错了 他还是会怪罪别人
how it was everybody else's fault when he was clearly in the wrong.
但是当我和我妹妹发现
But, you know, once my sister and I realized it was just an excuse
这只是他对家人不好的借口后 我们想通了
to treat his family like shit, it made life a little easier.
知道我们之间有什么区别吗？
You know what though? I see one difference between us.
-什么？ -我从来不犯错
Hmm? I'm never wrong.
你们俩都是同一类人渣
You are...You're two pricks in a pod.
我长得也像他吗？
Do I look like him as well?
嗯..
Mm...
不怎么像
Not really.
他不像我这样精致帅气吗？
- He wasn't exquisitely handsome?
不是这个 只是…
- It's not that, it's just...
你们的发型不一样
the hair... the hair is different.
-发型？ -对
- The hair? - Yeah.
他有点头发
He had some.
哦
Oh.
哦 我不能喝
Oh, I can't.
哦 没关系的 世界末日要来了
Oh, come on, the world is ending.
我想一杯威士忌改变不了什么
I really don't think a quarter-ounce of whiskey's gonna tip the scales, do you?
那好吧
Well...
我希望你是错的
I hope you're wrong.
剩下的不只是混蛋和死人
About the assholes and the dead.
我希望有更多种人
I hope there is more.
为希望有更多种人 干杯
Here's to hoping there is more.
-关上车库的门 -我来
- Close the garage. - I've got it.
等等
Wait. Wait. Wait.
-遮住眼睛 -好
- Cover your eyes. - Yeah.
关上了
Okay, okay, okay. It's closed. It's closed.
这些混蛋
Sons of bitches.
车到哪去了？
Where's the goddamn car?
露西和费利克斯去哪儿了？
You guys. You guys, where are Lucy and Felix?
操
Fuck.
（在河上已二十四小时）
你不划了
You stopped rowing.
我休息一下
I'm just taking a break.
还要多久？
How much longer?
几个小时
A few hours.
啊
Ah!
马洛里！
Malorie!
Malorie! Malorie!
救我！
Help!
马洛里！
Malorie!
你没事吧？
- Are you okay? Are you okay? - Yes.
-我冷 -我知道 等一下
- I'm cold. - I know. I know you're cold. Hold on.
不 我们所有吃的和毯子 该死！
No, no, no, no, no, no. All the food and blankets. God damn it!
-对不起 -没事
- I'm sorry. - No, no, it's...
等等
Hold on.
好 没事
Okay. All right.
-没事 -我好冷
- Okay. - I'm so cold.
我们会让你暖和起来的 好吗？
We're gonna get you warmed up, okay? We're gonna get you warmed up.
把毯子盖好
Put this around you.
眼罩不要摘掉 坐稳了
Keep your blindfolds on. Stay tight.
你们听见了吗？
Did you hear that?
躺在船底 躺好 躺平
Lay down on the bottom of the boat. Lay down, really flat.
你们一定要小声 我把鸟留在这里
I need you to be quiet. I'm gonna leave the birds with you.
我要把你们盖起来 不要发出声音 不要离开船
I'm gonna cover you up, but do not make a sound and do not leave this boat.
明白吗？千万不能离开船
Understand? Do not leave this boat!
妈的！
Shit.
马洛里
Malorie.
马洛里出事了
Something is wrong with Malorie.
马洛里
Malorie.
啊 啊
Ah! Ah!
马洛里？
Malorie?
我让你待在船上的呢
I told you to stay on the boat.
你不需要思考
You don't think.
你按照我说的话做 不然你就会死 明白吗？
You do exactly what I say or you die, do you understand me?
万一我出了事 不要来救我
If something happens to me, do not try and help me.
一定要抛下我 救你自己
Forget about me and try to save yourself.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
说！万一我出了事 你怎么办？
Say it! If something happens to me, what do you do?
救你自己 快说！
You save yourself. Say it!
-我会救我自己 -你救你自己
- I save myself. - You save yourself.
我没法儿信任你了
I can't trust you.
世界末日会让我们做出疯狂的事
The end of the world makes us do things.
这不是世界末日
- It's not the end of the world.
真的吗？
- Really?
感觉好像
It sure feels like it.
在我被派去伊拉克的最后一段时间 我们驻扎在一个村里
At the end of my deployment in Iraq, we were stationed at this village...
我们奉命在街上巡逻 确保大家安全
ordered to patrol the streets, make sure everybody was safe.
有一天早晨 我们看到
One morning, we saw...
一个父亲带着他的四个孩子在走
this father walking with his four kids.
所以我停下来确保一切都没事
So I pulled over to make sure everything was okay
确保他安全到达他想去的地方
and to make sure he got wherever he was going safely.
后来知道 他是送他孩子上学
Come to find out, he was walking his kids to school.
在那片狼藉
In the middle of all that shit,
混乱之中 他在送他孩子上学
all that chaos, he was walking his kids to school.
所以
So...
我们就跟着他
So we just followed him.
日复一日
Day after day.
我们都会护送他
We escorted him.
这成为了我们的一个习惯
That just became our routine.
然后 在我们最后的日子
And then, at the end of our time,
当我要回家了的时候 他给了我这个
he gave me this when it was time to come back home.
嗯
Mm.
希望他依然还在送他孩子上学
I like to think he's still walking his kids to school.
（在河上已二十八小时）
喂 有人听到吗？喂
Hello, can anybody hear me? Hello?
我是马洛里 有人吗？能听见吗？喂
This is Malorie. Anybody, can you hear me? Hello?
有人听见吗？喂 有人听见吗？
Can anybody hear me? Hello? Hello? Can anybody hear me?
喂 信号测试 喂
Hello? Testing, hello?
喂 有人在吗？喂？
Hello, is anyone out there? Hello?
能听到吗，拜托？
Can you hear me, please?
-喂 信号测试 -你是…
- Hello? Testing. - Are you a...
你戴着眼罩吗？
Do you have a blindfold on?
你身后的毯子还挂着吗？
You do. Is-- Is the blanket behind you still up?
啊
Ah...
好 快点进来
Okay, just come in really, really quickly.
谢谢 我的眼罩在这里 非常感谢你
Thank you. Here's my blindfold. Thank you so much.
没事 在这里等一下 马洛里！
It's okay. Just wait. Wait here. Malorie!
-等等 -奥林匹亚 你在干什么？
- I gotta pee. - Olympia, what are you doing?
-马洛里！ -你在干什么？
- Malorie! - What are you doing?
-你怎么想的？趴下！ -他很害怕
- What are you thinking? Get down! - Okay, he's just scared.
-他很害怕 -检查他的包
- He's just scared. - Tom. Check the bag.
过来 奥林匹亚
Get over here, Olympia. Get over here.
-你是谁？ -这家伙是谁？
- Who are you? - Who is this guy?
汤姆 我看着他 检查他的包
Tom, I've got him. Check the bag. Check the bag.
-他是谁？ -他很害怕
- Who is this? - He's just scared.
-你是谁？ -他怎么进来的？
- Who are you? - How did he get in here?
-奥林匹亚 闭嘴 你是谁？ -他刚才很害怕 我就让他进来了
- Shut up, Olympia. Who are you? - He was scared, okay? I just let him in.
-你让一个陌生人到房子里来？ -对不起
- You let a stranger in the house! - I'm sorry.
-他吓坏了！ -你是傻子吗？
- He was terrified! - Are you a simpleton?
天呐 求你了
Oh, God. Okay. Please.
我名叫加里
My name is Gary.
我住在城里
I live in the city.
这些东西来的时候 我和我同事坐了出城的第一班列车
When these things came, I got the first train out with some colleagues
我们以为这样就会安全
because we thought it would be safe.
让我待在这里吧 拜托了 他们在找我
Please, please just let me stay here. They're after me.
谁在找你？
Who's after you?
-我不信 他在说谎 -谁在找你？
- I don't believe it. He's lying. - Who's after you?
显然他在说谎
It's obvious he's lying.
-我发誓 -你为什么来这里？
- I swear. - Why are you here?
我们藏到我同事卡尔家
We went to my colleague Carl's house to lay low.
原先一切都没事 后来他们闯了进来
Everything was fine until they broke in.
灵体不会闯进人家的
Creatures don't break into people's homes.
不 不是灵体 是这些疯子
No, not the creatures, these psychos.
诺斯伍德的疯子
These psychos from Northwood.
诺斯伍德？是哪里？
Northwood? I don't... Where is that?
是一个精神病院 专门收容那些犯罪的精神病人
It's a mental institution for the criminally insane.
这下可好 他们有了放风通行证
Well, it's nice to know they have hall passes now.
然后呢？
And then what?
他们把我们带到外面 逼我们睁开眼睛
They took us outside and they forced our eyes open
于是我们不得不看那些灵体
so that we would have to look at the creatures.
什么？
What?
-你看了吗？ -没有
- Did you look? - No.
我朋友卡尔把他们其中的一个人 摔倒在地上
Somehow, my friend Carl managed to tackle one of these people to the ground
然后我们都跑了
and the rest of us made a run for it.
我不停地跑 直到跑到了这里
I just kept on running and running and running till I got here.
我敲了每家每户的门 但没人开门
I've been knocking on all the doors and nobody answered.
最后你们开了门 所以…
Until you did, so...
谢谢你们
Thank you.
小鸟
Birds.
最可怕的是 当这些人闯进来的时候
The scariest thing was, uh... when these people broke in, they...
他们没有戴着眼罩
they weren't wearing blindfolds.
好像他们不需要
It's like they didn't need them.
如果它们在外面 你一定要戴眼罩
But they'd been outside. You have to wear blindfolds.
这些人不用
Not these people.
这些疯子不会像其他人一样受到影响
These crazy guys weren't affected like everyone else.
他们想看
They wanted to see.
他们很开心
They were happy.
他们可开心了
They were so glad.
他们说所有人都必需看到
And they said everyone needed to see.
等等
Wait.
起来 出去 这里不是孤儿院
Get up and get out. It's not an orphanage.
新来的 你来参观过了 我们很高兴认识你 现在滚吧
New guy, you had a great visit. We really loved meeting you. Now fuck off.
谁不同意 就和他一起走
And anybody who doesn't agree, you go with him.
-快点出去！ -道格拉斯 你这是谋杀
- Out now! - Douglas, that is murder.
不 这才是谋杀
No. This is murder.
-求你了 -让陌生人进屋
- Please. - Letting strangers into this house.
我们每次与外界接触 都带给了我们死亡
Every contact we have had with the outside has brought us death.
莉迪亚 格雷戈 查理
Lydia, Greg, Charlie.
你要是想救外面的人
If you wanna save people out there,
你就出了那扇门去救
then you go right through that door and you go do it.
我们不能再让更多陌生人进屋了
We're not bringing any more strangers in here.
只要我活着 就不行
Not while I'm alive.
我说最后一遍 站起来 出…
I won't tell you again, get up and get--
谢谢你
Thank you.
你睡车库
You'll sleep in the garage.
我开门的唯一原因是
The only reason I opened that door
我记得在那扇门外是什么感受
is 'cause I remember what it felt like to be outside of it.
要是你们没让我进来
If you guys hadn't let me in, I...
我感觉自己真是个累赘
I feel like such a burden.
你不会比我更是个累赘 好吗？
You are no more a burden than I am, okay?
-不是那样的 -是的
- That's not true. - It is. It is.
你不像我那么软弱
You're not soft like me.
我被宠坏了
I'm so spoiled.
我父母什么事都为我做 之后又有我丈夫宠我
My parents have always done everything for me and then my husband,
我被这些爱变软弱了
and I just... I got soft from all that love.
我是被一群狼养大的 你应该感到幸运才对
Well, I was raised by wolves, so consider yourself lucky.
如果我遭遇不幸 我想你照顾我的孩子
If something happens to me, I want you to take care of my baby.
行吗？
Okay?
-不 -求你了
- No. No. - Please.
-这是你的孩子 -马洛里
- It's your baby. - Malorie.
不
No.
-答应我 -你不会有事的
- Promise me. - Nothing is gonna happen to you.
这是你的孩子
It's your baby.
-答应我 -你不会…
- Promise me. - Nothing--
求你了 答应我
Please promise me.
嗯 好 当然
Yeah, okay. Yeah, of course.
这是什么？
What is this?
要是我打算告诉你
Well, if I was just gonna tell you,
我就不会包装的这么好了
I wouldn't have bothered putting it in this fancy-- this fancy bag.
我在拿食物用品的时候拿到的
I got it on the supply run.
好可爱
- It's so cute. - Mm-hmm.
-谢谢你 -不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
我知道这不是你理想中的迎婴洗礼
I know it's not the baby shower you've always dreamt of.
我非常喜欢
No, it's-- It's perfect.
等你宝宝长大了 你可以送给她 好吗？
And you can give it to your little one when she's old enough, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
（在河上已三十八小时）
河流加速了 我们现在开会
You guys, the river's speeding up. It's time for a meeting.
我要和你们讲关于急流的事
I need to talk to you about the rapids.
我们进入急流时 河水会非常颠簸
The rapids are where the water gets very bumpy.
声音会很响 非常危险
It's very loud. It's very dangerous,
这将会是我们最艰难的经历
and it's gonna be the hardest thing we have ever done.
当我们到达急流 你们其中一个人要做一件很重要的事
And when we reach them, one of you is gonna have a very important job.
你们其中一个人要看
One of you is gonna have to look.
看的那个人
And the person who looks,
要告诉我往哪个方向划
they have to tell me which direction to steer into
这样我才不会出错
so that I go the right way.
因为如果我看 我们都到不了
Because if I look, we won't make it.
要是我们看到什么怎么办？
What if we see something?
-我来 -不
- I'll do it. - No, no, no, no.
我说谁看
I'm-- I'm the one who will say who looks, okay? I say it.
明白吗？由我来说
我说谁去 我说谁看
I'll say who goes. I'll say who looks.
我说谁看
I say who looks.
∮ To live without you ∮
∮ Would only be heartbreak for me ∮
∮ I say a little prayer for you ∮
测试信号 有人在吗？
Testing. Testing. Hello? Hello? Is anyone out there?
喂 测试信号 一 二 三 喂
Hello? Testing, one, two, three. Hello?
测试信号
Testing.
∮ Forever and ever You'll stay in my heart ∮
-我很爱这首歌 -我也是
- I love this song. - Me too.
-我也是 -我也是
- Me too. - Me too.
我从来没听过
- I've never actually heard it before. - Hmm.
∮ Together forever That's how must be ∮
∮ To live without you Would only be heartbreak for me... ∮
-或许是虚惊一场呢？ -没事
- It could be a false alarm, right? - All right.
我们到楼上卧室里去
We're going upstairs to the bedroom.
我们需要毛巾、海绵、剪刀 还有很多水
We need towels, sponges, um... scissors, and lots of water.
很多桶水 没事的
Buckets of water. It's okay. It's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
慢点 有我在
Take it easy. I've got you.
没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
剪刀在你左手边的抽屉里
Ah, the scissors are in the, um, drawer by the side of your left hand. Yeah.
-你要生了 -不 不是的
- Okay, so the baby's coming. - No, not happening.
-不是的 -一定是的
- Not happening. - It's definitely coming.
-跟我来 -不 不是的
- Come with me. Come with me. - This is not happening.
你要生了 我们走 走吧
It's happening. Let's go. Come on. Hey.
-我得倒水 -我们来倒
- I have to do the water. - We'll do the water.
好 没事的
Okay, here we go.
-你们俩很棒 -闭嘴
- You two are doing great. - Oh, shut up.
再来一次
One more time.
再来
Come on. Come on.
没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
是个男孩
It's a boy.
哦
Oh.
但是
No.
你姨妈还以为你会是个女孩呢
And your auntie thought you'd be a girl.
嘿 新来的 让我进来
Hey, new guy. New guy, let me in.
过来把锁打开
Just come and unlock the door. Come on.
让我出来 你在干什么？
Let me out. What are you doing?
什么？
What?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
加里？
Gary?
加里！
Gary!
嘿
Hey.
汤姆！他把鸟放进冰柜了
Tom! He put the birds in the freezer.
汤姆 我和你说过他是个疯子
Tom, I told you he's fucking crazy.
加…
Ga--
汤姆 去拿散弹枪
Tom. Get the shotgun.
他疯了
He's crazy.
你在干什么？我们让你进屋
What the fuck are you doing? We let you into this house.
我们…
We let--
不要！见鬼
No! No! Fuck.
你这混蛋 我就知道你是个疯子
Fucking asshole. I knew you were a fucking lunatic.
你这个混蛋 我们救了你
You fucking piece of shit. We saved you.
操！
Fuck!
快好了 对 对
- Almost there. - That's right. That's right.
好！
Yes! Yes!
好
Yes.
你成功了 妈妈
Oh.You did it, Mama. You did it.
哦 你好
Oh. Hello.
你们真美丽
You look so beautiful.
下面发生什么了？
What's going on down there?
我可以看看吗？
Can I see?
真美
So beautiful.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我可以看看你的孩子吗？
Can I see yours?
哇
Wow.
Hum.
谢谢
Thank you.
看看这个
Look at this.
-天呐 奥林匹亚 遮住你的眼睛 -是不是很美？
- Olympia, cover your eyes. - Isn't it beautiful?
不 你为什么这样做？加里 别这样
No. Why are you doing this? Gary, please don't do this.
-看 -加里 别这样
- Look. - Gary, please don't do this.
-给孩子看 -不 奥林匹亚
- Show the baby. - No, no, no, Olympia.
奥林匹亚 遮住孩子的眼睛
Olympia, cover the baby's eyes.
奥林匹亚
Olympia.
看！
See?
-给你的孩子看 -奥林匹亚 让我看你的孩子
- Show your baby. - Olympia, let me see your baby.
-它们看上去不错 -奥林匹亚 让我看你的孩子
- You're not so bad. - Olympia, let me see your baby.
遮住孩子的眼睛 让我看你孩子 就一会儿
Keep the baby's eyes covered. Let me see your baby, just for one minute.
奥林匹亚 让我抱你孩子 就一会儿！
Olympia, let me hold your baby just for one minute!
就一会儿
Just one minute.
让我抱一会儿 好吗？
Let me hold her for one minute, okay?
-就一会儿 -看
- One minute. - See.
-好吗？ -看
- Okay? - See.
看！
See!
不 哦 求你了 不要
No. Oh, no. Oh, please, no. Oh!
-快看 -不
- See it. See it. - No, no, no. No, no, no.
嘿 马洛里
Hey, Malorie.
把孩子们给我
Give me the children.
Give me the kids.
把孩子们给我 不然我就抢了
Give me the children or I'll take them!
嘿 混蛋
Hey, asshole.
嘿
Hey.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
你是来看的吗？
Have you come to see?
睁开你的眼睛
Open your eyes.
别害怕
Don't be frightened.
看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
看着我！
Look at me. Look at me!
Ow.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 你没能看到
I'm sorry that you didn't get to see.
它真的很美
It is beautiful.
太美了
So beautiful.
对不起
I'm sorry.
它将净化这个世界
It shall cleanse the world.
求你了 别伤害我们 别靠近我们
Please don't. Please don't hurt us. Please stay away from us.
求你了 求你了
Please. Please. Please. Please.
不要这样做
Please don't do this. Don't do this. Please don't do this.
没事了
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
（五年后）
仔细听喀哒声
Listen to the clicks.
听这声音 是更轻还是更响
Listen to the sounds, if they're softer or louder.
听这个
Listen to this.
听
Listen.
当声音更响时 你们就在一个 宽阔的空间 听到了吗？
If they're louder, you're in an open space. Do you hear that?
如果声音更轻的话 代表着周围有东西
But if they're softer, something is very close.
喂 有人吗？
Please. Anyone. Hello? Hello?
喂
Hello, hel--
Hello?
看这个。 是的
Check it out. Yeah.
这里什么都没有
There is nothing here.
-去另一个地方吧。- 浪费时间
- Let's go to another spot. - Fucking time.
嘿
- Hey.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我又听到那些人了
I heard some of them again.
什么？
What?
有几个人
A few of 'em...
在开车
driving around.
从开车的方式看 好像他们没有戴眼罩
Driving around like they're not blindfolded.
好吧
Okay.
那就不要再一个人出去
No more runs alone.
好
Okay.
这是什么？
What's this?
我想给孩子们一个警报系统
I was thinking like a warning system for the kids.
如果他们遇到麻烦 就摇铃
- If they're in trouble, ring the bell.
嗯 不错
- Right. That's nice.
那这个呢？
How about this?
哦 这是…
Oh, it's...
纯粹为了生存着想
It's purely survival.
-纯粹为了生存？ -没错
- Purely survival? - Yeah.
喂
Hello?
有人在吗？喂
Is anyone there? Hello?
测试信号
Testing. Testing.
有人在的话 请回话
If there is anyone there, please respond.
-喂 -喂
- Hello? - Hello.
你是谁？
Who is this?
-我名叫瑞克 -不
My name is Rick.
你是谁？
Who is this?
瑞克 我是汤姆
Rick, this is Tom.
我们有一个地方
We have a place.
一个营地 有足够的供给…
A compound with enough supplies--
我们有一个社区
We have a community.
这里很安全
It's safe here.
我们在河的最下游
We're down by the river's end.
-你在哪儿？ -别回答他
- Where are you? - Don't answer that.
派克采石场附近
Near Pike's Quarry.
天呐 你们好远 你们有几个人？
Jesus. You're a ways away. How many of you are there?
四个
- Four of us. - Hmm-mm.
其中有小孩吗？
Are any of them children?
-什么都别说 -没事的
- Don't, do not say anything. - It's okay. It's okay.
没有 怎么了？
No. Why?
因为沿着河过来是到这里最快的方式
Because the fastest way to get here is by the river,
恐怕你带着小孩来不了
and I don't think you could make it with kids.
等等 沿着河？
Wait, the river?
向下游一直漂
Float downstream as far as you can.
直到你们到达急流
Stay on the water until you hit the rapids.
那里水流湍急 非常危险
The water is fast there. It's dangerous.
我们有几个人丢了性命
We've lost some people.
你们得看清楚
You need to see clearly.
-什么意思？ -你说看清楚是什么意思？
- What does that mean? - What do you mean, see clearly?
你们得看
You will have to look.
瑞克 我们都戴着眼罩 我们看不了
- I'm telling you. - Rick, we'll have blindfolds on.
你这样说我就放心了
We can't look.
I'm glad you said that.
其中一定要有一个人…
Someone will have to take a--
按流速计算 你们要准备好大概两天的旅程
Prepare for two days' journey at the pace of the river's current.
带超过两天需要的补给
Bring supplies for longer.
急流过后怎么找你呢？瑞克
How do I find you after the rapids, Rick?
你们会听见鸟声
You'll hear the birds.
我们有很多鸟 跟着声音走
We've got a lot of them. Just follow the sound to us.
顺着河边小道 你们会碰到一面墙 墙上有一扇门
Down a small embankment, you'll find a wall with a gate.
那是我们的…
That's our--
-他们的什么？ -我们的什么？
- That's their what? - That's our what?
瑞克？
Rick?
有可能是真的
It could be real.
-不 -或许是事实
- No. - Could be the truth.
-“或许”还不够 -万一瑞克能帮我呢？
- Could be is not good enough. - What if Rick could help us?
万一瑞克和那帮人是一伙的呢？
And what if Rick is one of them?
但他知道鸟的事
Huh? Wait, he knew about the birds.
天呐 加里也知道鸟的事 他把鸟放进冰柜
Oh, my God. Gary knew about the birds and he put them in the freezer.
我不敢相信你真的在考虑这件事
I cannot believe you're actually thinking about this.
每家房子都没食物了 我们得走了
Every house has run out of food. We have to move.
你真的以为我不知道吗？
You really don't think I know that? You don't think I know that?
我小时候 我们家有条像这样的船
When I was little, we had a boat just like this.
每年夏天 我们会把船拉到湖上
And every single summer, we would take it to the lake.
每年夏天都会
Every summer.
你们一定会很喜欢那里的 那里有树 有花
You guys would have loved it up there. They had trees. They had flowers.
湖水很暖和 天上飘着云
The water was warm, the clouds were in the sky.
所有孩子都在水里玩
We'd all play in the water. All the kids, all the children.
我们都会在水里与岸上来回跑
We would all just run up and down the shore.
世界上有别的孩子吗？
There were other children in the world?
有啊 就像你们一样
Yeah, just like you. Just like you.
像你们一样
Like you.
有一天我们看到了一棵巨大的橡树
One day, we saw this really, really big oak tree.
比这个房子还要大
It was bigger than this house.
大到我们连树顶都看不到
It was so big and old, I couldn't see the top of it.
-猜我们做了什么？ -爬了树
- Guess what we did? - Climbed it.
没错 我们爬了上去
We climbed it. Yes, we climbed it.
我们不断地爬 一直爬到树顶
We climbed it and climbed it until we got to the top.
猜我们爬到树顶后看到了什么？
Guess what we saw when we got to the top?
男孩！女孩！该睡觉了
Boy! Girl! Time for bed.
但汤姆在讲故事
But Tom's telling a story.
-就让我…快讲完了 -我不说第二遍 走了
- Mal, let me just-- We're almost done. - I'm not gonna say it again. Come on.
女孩 走了
Girl, come on.
快点
Right now.
走了
Come on.
快点
Right now.
上床！
Bed!
-你在干什么？ -你在干什么？
- What are you doing? - What are you doing?
现在他们就会以为 他们会和别的孩子去爬树
Now they think they're gonna go outside and climb trees with all these new kids
-看花草 看蝴蝶！ -这只是个故事
- and see butterflies and flowers! - It's a story.
这不是故事 这是个谎言
It's not a story. It's a lie.
因为他们永远不会爬树 他们永远不会交新朋友
Because they'll never climb trees, they are never gonna make new friends.
-为什么要他们相信这些？ -他们总得相信些什么
- Why make them believe that? - They have to believe in something.
要是他们什么都不信 做这些有什么意义？
What is this for if they don't have anything to believe in?
-为了他们能生存 -生存并不是生活
- So that they survive! - Surviving is not living.
听你的 他们会死的！
They're gonna die if they listen to you!
生活不仅是生活本身 更是它蕴含的可能性
Life is more than just what is. It's what could be.
你能把它变成什么
What you could make it.
就算你知道不可能实现 你也要给他们梦想
You need to promise them dreams that may never come true.
你明知道随时可能失去他们 但你会一样地去爱他们
You need to love them knowing that you may lose them at any second.
他们值得拥有梦想、爱和希望 他们值得拥有一个母亲
They deserve dreams. They deserve love. They deserve hope. They deserve a mother.
他们值得拥有一个母亲
They deserve a mother.
你还没给他们取名 马洛里 他们还是叫男孩、女孩
You haven't given them names, Mal. Their names are Boy and Girl!
想想吧
Think about that.
我做的每一个决定都是为了他们
Every single decision I have made has been for them.
每一个决定
Every single one.
你知道我看到了什么吗？
You know what I saw?
在树顶上？
At the top of the tree?
我看到一个鸟窝
I saw a nest.
有五只鸟
With five birds.
在最顶端的树枝上
Sitting on the top branch.
然后它们都飞走了
And then they just flew away.
好 坐下！
Got it. Got it. Sit. Sit!
这里安全 进来吧
It's safe. Come in.
哇
Wow.
真的吗？
No, you did not.
-估计变质了 -是啊
- They're probably stale. - Yeah.
过来
Come here.
我就喜欢这样的
Just how I like 'em.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-抱歉 -我也是
- Sorry. - Me too.
过来
Come here.
孩子们
Kids.
这是草莓
This is strawberry.
草莓就是这个味道的
This is what strawberry tastes like.
-那是什么？ -安静
- What's that? - Quiet.
嘘
Shh.
有人在家吗？
Anybody home?
带孩子们从后门走 我引开他们
Take the kids out the back. I'll distract them.
如果我过15分钟还不回家的话 你就带着孩子们坐船走
If I'm not home in 15 minutes, you take the kids to the boat and you go.
-我不会离开你！ -马洛里
- I'm not leaving you! - Mal.
-不 我不会离开你 -听我说
- No, I'm not leaving you. - Listen to me.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
我爱你 快走
I love you. Go.
-不！ -快走 求你了
- No! - Go. Please go.
保重 快走
Be good. Go.
走！
Go!
我出来了！
I'm coming out!
-你好 朋友 -有什么要帮忙的吗？
- Hey there, friend. - Can I help you?
不用了 朋友
I don't think so, friend.
但我们可以帮你
We can help you though.
不 离开！
No. Go!
-把眼罩摘下 -退后
- Take off your blindfold. - Stand back.
-退后！ -她不会动的
- Stand back! - She's not moving.
哎 这里有个女的带着两个孩子
Hey. Got a woman and two kids over here.
它们要来了
They're coming.
它们不会伤害你的
They won't hurt you.
豁出去了
Fuck it. Fuck it.
相反
On the contrary...
它是很美丽的 朋友
it's a beautiful thing, friend.
听好了 我只说一遍
Listen to me. I'm only gonna say this once.
我们要起程了 这次旅程会很艰苦
We are going on the trip now. It's going to be rough.
你们必须严格按照我说的去做 不然我们到不了
You have to do every single thing I say or we will not make it.
明白吗？
Understand?
汤姆呢？
Where's Tom?
他不来了
He's not coming.
（在河上已四十二小时）
是时候了
It's time. It's time. It's time.
记得急流吗？
You remember the rapids?
还记得我说的急流吗？
Remember I told you about the rapids?
我们离它很近了
Well, they're close.
急流非常危险 我们想要渡过只有一个办法
It is very dangerous and there's only one way for me to navigate through them.
必须有人得看
Somebody has to look.
-我来看 -不 我会决定！明白吗？
- I'll look. - No. I will decide! Okay? I will decide.
让我想一下
Just give me-- Just give me a second.
我看
I'll do it.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
谁也不看
Nobody's looking.
好吗？我们谁也不看
Okay, nobody's looking.
好吗？
Okay?
我们把眼睛蒙上
Do your eyes. Let's do eyes.
跪下来 趴下来 抓紧了
Come on. Get on your knees. Stay down low. Hold on tight.
别动 抓紧了
Don't move. Hold tight.
抓紧 别松手 我们没事的
Hold tight. Don't let go. We're gonna be okay.
抓紧！
Hold on!
Please hold on. Hold on!
啊
Ah!
女孩！男孩！
Girl! Boy!
Girl! Boy! Boy?
女孩！
Girl!
马洛里
Malorie.
男孩！
Boy!
-再叫！ -救命！
- Keep calling me! - Help!
-马洛里 -再叫
- Malorie. - Keep calling me.
马洛里！
Malorie!
-我在这里 -马洛里！
- I'm right here. - Malorie!
-我来了 你在哪？ -马洛里
- I'm coming. Where are you? - Malorie.
女孩呢？女孩？
Where's Girl? Girl? Girl?
继续摇铃 我听见你了
Keep ringing. I hear you. Keep ringing.
继续摇 女孩
Keep ringing, Girl.
继续摇
Keep ringing. Keep ringing.
好孩子
Good girl.
干得好 起来 站起来
Okay. Good job. Get up. Stand up.
哦，好的 好的
Oh, good. Good, good, good.
好孩子 你们听到那些鸟叫声吗？
Good girl. Okay. Do you guys hear those birds?
我们要往那个方向去 跟着声音走
That's where we're headed. We just follow that sound.
待在我身后
Stay behind me.
呆瓜 嘿 呆瓜
Dumb-dumb. Hey, dumb-dumb.
睁开眼睛 马洛里 呆瓜 我在这里
Open your eyes, Malorie. Dummy. I'm right here.
不
No, no, no, no, no.
你不是真的
No, you're not.
不
No, no, no. No, no, no.
马洛里 看着我
Malorie, look at me.
看着我 马洛里 看着我
Look at me. Malorie, look at me.
-马洛里 看着我 -这不是真的
- Malorie, look at me. - It's not real. It's not real.
这不是真的 这不是真的
It's not real. It's not real. it's not real.
-马洛里？ -马洛里？
- Malorie? - Malorie?
马洛里？
Malorie?
马洛里
Malorie. Malorie.
马洛里 看着我 马洛里
Look at me, Malorie.
-男孩 女孩 -马洛里
- Boy. Girl. - Malorie.
别动 待在原地！
Don't move. Stay right where you are!
睁开眼睛
Open your eyes.
马洛里 睁开你的眼睛
Malorie, open your eyes.
男孩 女孩
Boy. Girl. Where are you?
你们在哪儿？
跟我来 看着我
Come with me. Look at me.
我需要你 看着我
I need you. Just look at me.
我真的可以把眼罩摘下吗？
Can I really take off my blindfold?
-男孩！ -安全吗？
- Boy! - It's safe?
不 那不是我
No, that's not me.
不 别摘眼罩
No, no, no. Keep your blindfold on.
那不是真的 男孩
Boy, that's not real.
别摘眼罩 听我说
Keep your blindfold on. Listen to me.
听我的声音 这是我的声音！
Listen to my voice! This is my voice!
女孩 跟我来 看着我
Girl, come with me. Look at me.
把眼罩摘下 你可以看着我
Take the blindfold off. You can look at me.
我看了不会有危险吗？
Isn't it dangerous if I look?
不 我在这里 不能把眼罩摘下
No. No, I'm right here. I'm right here! Do not take off your blindfold!
请听我说！
Please listen to me!
-马洛里 -什么？不
- Malorie. - What? No.
-把眼睛睁开 -不 女孩 喊我
- Please open your eyes. - No. Girl, call out to me.
-简直太美了 -喊我！你在哪儿？
- It's just beautiful. - Call out to me, please. Where are you?
男孩 女孩 你们在哪儿？ 不要带走我的孩子们！
Boy. Girl. Where are you? Don't take my children.
不要带走我的孩子们！
Do not take my children!
继续摇铃 宝贝
Oh, baby, keep ringing. Keep ringing.
继续摇 宝贝 我来了
Keep ringing, baby. I'm coming. Keep ringing.
继续摇
Come on, keep ringing. Keep ringing.
哦 上帝 我找到你了
Oh, my God. I've got you.
没事了 我们没事 女孩呢？
I've got you. We're good. Where's Girl? Where's Girl? Where's Girl?
女孩 女孩！
Girl. Girl! Girl!
女孩哪儿去了？
Where's Girl?
她怕你
She's scared of you.
什么？
What?
她怕你
She's scared of you.
It's okay.
呃
Uh...
哦 我真抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
我真抱歉 姑娘
I'm so sorry, sweet girl. I'm so sorry.
我错了 我不该那么凶
I was wrong. I shouldn't have been so harsh.
我不该阻止你们玩
I shouldn't have stopped you from playing.
我不该打断汤姆的故事 因为故事还没讲完
I shouldn't have ended Tom's story because it wasn't finished.
当他爬到大橡树顶
When he climbed to the very top of that giant oak tree,
他看到了最美的东西
he saw the most beautiful things.
他看到了数百个孩子在玩耍
He saw hundreds of children playing games.
好几百
Hundreds.
他还看到了鸟
And he saw birds...
不同颜色的鸟
all different colored birds,
他还看到了我们
and... and he saw us.
他从树顶上看到了我们
He saw us from the very top.
他看到我们在一起 我们一定要待在一起
He saw us together, and we have to be together.
这不只是个故事
And it's not just a story.
因为我有好多东西想给你们看
It's not, because I have so much I want to show you.
我想让你们看到的东西太多了
I have so much I want you to see. Okay?
但是我们得一起努力 好吗？
But we have to do it together, okay?
所以我现在要你到我这边来 好吗？
So I just need you to come to me right now, okay? Please?
到我身边来
Just come to me.
宝贝 到我身边来 好吗？
Baby, come to me, okay?
哦 啊
Oh! Ah.
我非常爱你 我非常爱你
I love you so much. I love you so much. I love you so much.
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
我要找到那群鸟 知道吗？找到鸟
We need to find the birds, okay? Find the birds.
我要你们留意鸟的叫声 好吗？
I want you to listen for the birds, okay?
听鸟叫声
Listen for the birds.
知道吗？听鸟叫声
Okay, listen for the birds.
听鸟叫声 仔细听好
Listen for the birds. Just listen for the birds.
马洛里！
Malorie.
安静 安静
Be quiet. Quiet. Quiet. Quiet.
我知道你很害怕 但是是我
Malorie, I know you're scared, but it's me.
拜托 你在哪里 马洛里？我需要帮忙
Please. Where are you, Mal? I need help!
就看一下 来找我
Just take a peek and find me.
快走
Come on.
朝鸟的方向走 鸟在哪儿？
Go to the birds. Where are the birds?
鸟在哪儿？
Where are the birds? The birds. Where are the birds?
那边
That way.
我听不见鸟叫
I can't hear the birds! I can't hear the birds!
太响了太吵了
It's too loud. It's too noisy!
马洛里！
Malorie!
太吵了！
It's too loud!
这边！
This way!
有台阶
Step. Step.
你好！
Hello! Hello! Hello!
开门 拜托了！
Open the door. Please open the door!
我叫马洛里 我有孩子
My name is Malorie. I'm Malorie. I have children.
请你找到瑞克 并且告诉他 我们沿着河 跟着鸟叫声来的
Please find Rick and tell Rick we followed the river and we followed the birds.
马洛里！
Malorie!
-救命！求你了！ -看着我 马洛里！
- Help! - Please! - Look at me, Malorie!
马洛里！
Malorie.
把孩子们带进去
Okay. Just take the children. Just take the children.
把孩子们带进去 他们只是孩子 让我的孩子们进去！
Take the children. They're just children. Please let my children in!
-求你了 开门！ -看着我
- Please! Open the door! - Look at me!
让我看你们的眼睛！
Let me see your eyes! Let me see your eyes!
好
Okay.
她没事
She's okay.
她没事 他们没事
She's okay. They're all okay.
把瑞克找来
Get Rick.
没事的
It's okay.
-马洛里？ -嗯
Malorie?
Yes.
我是瑞克
I'm Rick.
跟我来
Come with me.
好
Okay.
这边
Right this way.
你们在室内 你们安全了
You're inside and you're safe.
你们可以摘下眼罩了
You can take your blindfolds off.
（珍妮特塔克盲人学校）
跟我来
Come with me.
这些鸟
The birds.
当那些东西接近时 鸟会给人警告
They warn the sighted people whenever those things are around.
虽然不怎么管用 但总比没有强
It's not much, but it's something.
我去给你拿一点干的衣服
I'm going to get you some dry clothes.
嘿
Hey.
让小鸟去找它们的朋友 你们说怎么样？
What do you guys say we let the birds go and be with their friends?
好吗？
Shall we do that?
好
Okay.
马洛里？
Malorie?
马洛里·海斯？
Malorie Hayes?
拉帕姆医生
Dr. Lapham.
你们叫什么名字？
And what are your names?
女孩
Girl.
男孩
Boy.
其实
Actually...
你的名字是奥林匹亚
your name is Olympia.
嗯
Yeah.
跟我见过最善良的女孩起同一个名字
Named after the sweetest girl I ever met.
还有你的名字
And your name...
你的名字是汤姆
Your name is Tom.
汤姆
Tom.
我是他们的母亲
And I am their mother.
你们想和别的孩子一起玩吗？
Would you like to play with the other kids?
你想去玩吗？
You want to go play?
谢谢你 非常感谢你
Thank you. Thank you very much.